Now looking at our list of tasks to do,
انظر الآن إلى المهمام المطلوب القيام بها،
we could tackle them from the top to bottom.
يمكننا معالجتها من أعلى لأسفل.
So remember in the last lesson I mentioned that there are a number of
تذكر في الدرس الماضي ذكرت أن هناك عددًا من
ways that you can prioritize your tasks.
الطرق التي يمكنك من خلالها تحديد أولويات المهام.
So one way go about this is to try the hardest or
واحدة من تلك الطرق تهتم بمعالجة المهام الأصعب أو
riskiest tasks first making sure that that feature is even possible.
الأخطر، لذا تأكد أولًا أن الميزة يُمكن تفعيلها.
Now for us, we've never played an audio file before, so
بالنسبة لنا، لم نشغِّل ملف صوتي من قبل، ولذا
let's just make sure that even works.
دعونا فقط نتأكد من أنها تعمل.
So, the lowest risk item on this list is adding the play button icon
العنصر الأقل خطورة في هذه القائمة هو إضافة رمز زر التشغيل
to the list items and this is because we've modified layouts before so
إلى عناصر القائمة، وذلك بسبب تعديل مخططاتنا قبل ذلك
we know that this is possible.
لذلك نحن نعرف أن هذا ممكن.
So, let's go ahead and save this UI change for
دعونا نكمل، ونحفظ هذا التغيير الذي طرأ على واجهة المستخدم
the end of the lesson when we go ahead and do the visual polish.
لنهاية الدرس عندما نكمل مع تحسين الرؤية.
To get started, we're going to have you create a tiny music player app
للبدء، نحن نساعدك في إنشاء تطبيق مشغل موسيقى صغير
separate from the me walk app.
منفصل عن تطبيق لغة ميوك.
Developers often write a small app to test a new technology before building it
غالبًا ما يكتب المطورون تطبيقًا صغيرًا لاختبار تقنية جديدة قبل إنشائها
into their own larger app.
في تطبيقهم الأكبر.
Now by creating this sample app, you'll become familiar with
والآن بإنشاء هذا التطبيق العينة ستصبح أكثر معرفة بـ
the MediaPlayer API, and by the way, you may hear the term API come up
واجهة مشغل الوسائط، وبالمناسبة قد تسمع مصطلح واجهة تطبيقات البرامج
occasionally and that's just an acronym for application programming interface.
أحيانًا، وهذا مجرد اختصار لتطبيق واجهة البرمجة.
So when we talked about interfaces earlier,
لذلك، عندما تحدثنا عن الواجهات في وقت سابق،
remember they're like contracts that Android provides promising certain
تذكر أنها تشبه العقود التي يقدمها آندرويد ويعد بوظائف معينة
functionality, so things like playing media using the MediaPlayer class.
مثل تشغيل الوسائط باستخدام فئة مشغل الوسائط
So we don't need to know all the details within the MediaPlayer class,
لذلك نحن لسنا بحاجة إلى معرفة كل التفاصيل داخل فئة مشغل الوسائط،
things like like how gets the sound to come out of the speakers on a device,
بعض الأشياء مثل كيفية خروج الصوت من مكبرات الصوت في جهاز،
but as a developer, we just care that we can use the MediaPlayer and
ولكن بصفتي مطور، نهتم فقط أن تتمكن من استخدام مشغل الوسائط
call methods on it to play media files.
وطرق تشغيل ملفات الوسائط
Right, for this quiz,
حسنًا، بالنسبة لهذا الاختبار،
you'll be building this simplified music player app that works for a single song.
سيُطلب منك إنشاء تطبيق مشغل موسيقى بسيط يستطيع تشغيل أغنية واحدة.
So in this app, hitting Play
ومن ثم في هذا التطبيق، النقر للتشغيل
[MUSIC]
[MUSIC]
plays a song and hitting Pause, pauses the song.
يشغِّل الأغنية، والنقر فوق إيقاف مؤقت، يوقف تشغيل الأغنية مؤقتًا.
Now when you hit Play again, it's going to resume where it was paused.
وعند النقر فوق تشغيل مرة أخرى، يستأنف حيث تم إيقافه.
[MUSIC]
[MUSIC]
First create a new project in Android Studio and
أولًا أنشئ مشروع جديد في آندرويد ستوديو
start with the empty activity template and go ahead and build out this layout.
وابدأ مع قالب النشاط الفارغ واستمر في بناء هذا المخطط.
In the notes below the quiz, we've provided a link to help find and
في الملاحظات الواردة أسفل الاختبار، قدمنا رابطًا للمساعدة، ابحث عنه
download sample MP3 files for your app.
وقم بتنزيل ملفات MP3 عينة لتطبيقك.
Note that you could also use your own MP3 files if you want.
لاحظ أيضًا أنه يمكنك استخدام ملفات MP3 لديك إذا كنت تريد.
Be sure that the audio file is stored in the raw folder
تأكد من تخزين الملف الصوتي في المجلد البسيط
within the res directory of the app.
ضمن دليل موارد التطبيق.
To create the raw folder, within the project structure tab of your app,
لإنشاء المجلد البسيط ضمن علامة تبويب بنية المشروع في تطبيقك،
right-click on the res folder &gt; New &gt;
انقر بزر الماوس الأيمن على مجلد الموارد واختر
Android resource directory, then name the new directory raw,
دليل موارد آندرويد "جديد"، ثم اعط الدليل الجديد اسم raw
r-a-a, and choose its resource type to be raw as well, and then hit OK.
r-a-w، واختر نوع المورد ليكون بسيط أيضًا ثم اضغط موافق.
Then you can copy and paste the song file into this raw folder.
ثم يمكنك نسخ ملف الأغنية ولصقه في هذا المجلد البسيط.
Our MP3 file is a pre-encoded file that needs to be processed as is or raw.
ملف MP3 هو ملف مشفر مسبقا يحتاج إلى معالجته كما هو أو بسيط.
For a more detailed description on resource folders, check out
للحصول على وصف أكثر تفصيلا في مجلدات الموارد، اطلع على
the providing resources article in the notes below the quiz and then we'd
مقالة الموارد المقدمة في الملاحظات أسفل الاختبار وبعد ذلك
like you to add the provided audio file to the res/raw directory of your app.
سنطلب منك إضافة ملف الصوت المقدم إلى دليل الموارد/بسيط في تطبيقك.
Then I'd like you to modify the code by adding on-click listeners
ثم أود منك تعديل الشفرة من خلال إضافة مستمعين عند النقر
to make each of the buttons actually play and pause the song.
لجعل جميع الأزرار تشغل الأغنية وتوقفها مؤقتًا.
Also give it a try and
جربها
experiment with other functionality provided by the MediaPlayer class.
مع الوظائف الأخرى التي تقدمها فئة مشغل الوسائط.
So for example, you can try adding a button that changes the volume or
مثال، يمكنك إضافة زر يغير مستوى الصوت أو
even skips the middle of the song.
حتى يتخطى إلى وسط الأغنية.
So for this task,
بالنسبة لهذه المهمة،
you'll need to research how to use the MediaPlayer on Android.
ستحتاج إلى البحث عن كيفية تشغيل مشغل الوسائط في آندرويد.
To make this all work, we won't provide you the exact website to reference.
ولفعل ذلك، لن نوفر لك الموقع الدقيق ليكون مرجعًا.
Instead, take a look at tutorials on MediaPlayer in Android on your own and
بدلًا من ذلك، ألق نظرة على الدروس التعليمية الخاصة بمشغل الوسائط في آندرويد
then do some trial and error on your app to make it work.
ثم جرِّب واخطأ حتى تنجح في تشغيل تطبيقك.
So best of luck.
حظًا سعيدًا.